你在被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监视你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
我会知道  因为它是我造的
I know because... I built it.
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖活动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
它看到了与普通人相关的暴力罪行
Violent crimes involving ordinary people.
像你一样的普通人
People like you.
而政府认为这些罪行无关紧要
Crimes the government considered irrelevant.
他们不肯作为  所以我决定插手
They wouldn't act, so I decided I would.
但我需要一个搭档
But I needed a partner--
一个有能力介入其中的人
Someone with the skills to intervene.
因为受到当局追捕  我们只能秘密合作
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You will never find us.
不管你是被害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
如果你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
If you're number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪 第1季 第13集
Person of Interest S01E13 720p HDTV x264
早上好  里瑟先生
Good morning, mr. Reese.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese?
信号不太好
A bit of a bad connection.
你说服比利克先生
Were you able to convince mr. Billick
不要杀他的前妻了吗
to abandon his plan to kill his ex-wife?
我正在努力  芬奇
I'm working on it, Finch.
芬奇  什么事
Yeah, Finch. What is it?
这肯定违反了假释条例  泰迪
Pretty sure that's a parole violation, Teddy.
芬奇
Hello, Finch.
比利克刚跟我达成了共识
Billick and I just came to an understanding.
很好  我们又有新号码了
Good, because we have a new number.
我就知道你要说这个
Had a feeling you were going to say that.
地址我发给你了
I'm sending you an address.
到了给我个电话
Call me when you get there.
你确定就用他吗
You sure he's the right guy?
他再好不过
He's perfect.
这家伙有什么背景  芬奇
So what's this guy's story, Finch?
斯科特・鲍威尔  38岁
Scott Powell, 38.
是市里一个建筑项目的经理
He's a construction project manager for the city.
看来只是个居家好男人
Seems like a family man.
他老婆叫莱丝丽
His wife's name is Leslie.
儿子叫欧文  女儿叫米娅
Son is Owen, daughter Mia.
我的老天
Oh, my goodness.
你在画什么  一只小狗狗
What are you working on there? A doggie?
一匹马
A horse.
是匹马  当然是匹马
It's a horse. Of course it's a horse.
我知道这是马  我就是考考你
I knew it was a horse. I was just testing.
你的表丢了吗
Did you lose your watch?
没有  就是随手放在哪了
Uh, no. It's around here somewhere.
好了  宝贝们  爸爸要去上班了
All right, guys, daddy's got to go to work.
-拜拜  -我爱你  宝贝
-All right. Bye. - Love you, baby.
-我也爱你  -走了
- You too. Be good. - All right.
你还在吗  里瑟先生
Are you still there, mr. Reese?
你向往过更平常的生活吗  芬奇
You ever crave a more conventional life, finch?
如果你的"平常"是指没有号码的生活
If by "Conventional" you mean a life without the numbers,
有时会想到
It has crossed my mind.
鲍威尔的生活看起来很平常
It looks like Powell has a pretty normal one.
我们俩的经历能证明一件事
If there's one thing our little venture has proven,
里瑟先生  人们从来都表里不一
mr. Reese, it's that people are rarely what they seem.
芬奇  鲍威尔似乎翘班了
Finch, looks like Powell's playing hooky.
他正走向一个公园
He's heading into a park.
可能是去见人
Could be meeting somebody.
你追踪到他的手机了吗
Are you up on his phone?
马上
I'm about to be.
你好
Hi, yeah.
我想应聘你们报纸上
Calling about the installer job you have listed
登的安装工人岗位
in the-- in the paper here.
很抱歉  先生  我们已经招满了
I'm sorry, sir. That position's been filled.
好吧  那你们还有
Oh. Um, well, do you have
什么缺人的岗位吗  或者...
any other positions available at this time? Or--
芬奇  鲍威尔没有翘班
Finch, Powell's not skipping work,
他下岗了
He's out of work.
是的
Yes.
我刚发现市内登记的雇员名单
I'm just discovering that the city's employee directory
非常旧了
is grossly out of date.
有一场大规模公职人员裁员
A casualty of public employee cutbacks.
这场裁员让鲍威尔丢了工作
The same cutbacks have put mr. Powell out of a job--
就在八个月前
Eight months ago.
就他和家人的互动来看
Judging by the way he was acting with his family,
他们还蒙在鼓里
They have no idea.
他很长时间没有薪水可领了
That's a long time to go without a paycheck.
这些长笛是镀银的
These flutes are silver plated.
还是雕花的  但我觉得
And engraved. I ain't expecting
除了你们两口子没人要这玩意
another Leslie and Scott to come in the shop.
这些我都不要
Look, I can't use any of this stuff.
如果你还有手表
Now, if you have another watch
像上次那块那样...
Like you had the last time...
纽约互惠银行
这些只要100块
I'll let you have all of it for 100 bucks.
-抱歉  - 50块
- Sorry. - 50.
老兄  快拿着你的垃圾走人吧
Look, pal, take your junk and clear out, all right?
不准说这些是垃圾
Don't call my stuff junk!
你想让我叫警察来吗
Hey, you want I should call the cops?
不
No, man.
芬奇  他正处于人生低谷
Finch, this guy's about ready to hit rock bottom.
我查了鲍威尔的信用卡记录
I ran Powell's credit.
他刷爆了所有信用卡
He's maxed out on every one of his cards
除了和他老婆共用的那张
with the exception of the one he shares with his wife.
但那张也快到极限了
And that's almost at its limit.
你觉得他是个威胁吗
You suspect he might be a threat?
他刚差点为了点钱把个典当商的头剁掉
He just about took a pawnbroker's head off For a few bucks.
看看卡特警探能查到这家伙什么资料
See if detective carter can run a background check on this guy.
怎么不找弗斯科警探
What about detective Fusco?
他现在有别的事要忙
He's handling another matter right now.
搞清楚鲍威尔在搞什么名堂之前
I'll keep a close eye on Powell
我都会盯紧他
until we know what we're dealing with.
很好  我这就去
Good. And I'm going to want
查查他的电脑
to get a look at his home computer.
晚上和你会合
So I'll be joining you tonight.
是嘛  你以前监视过没有  芬奇
Really. Ever been on a stakeout, finch?
没有  我该带什么家伙吗
No. Should I bring anything?
厚外套  打发时间的书
Warm clothes, something to read,
-再带个空瓶子  -空瓶子
- And an empty water bottle. - Empty?
监视的时候可没厕所给你上  芬奇
There are no bathrooms on a stakeout, Finch.
他的双重生活过得挺得心应手
He's getting good at leading two lives.
很不幸  离露馅不远了
Unfortunately, they're on a collision course.
这就饿了嘛  芬奇
Hungry already, finch?
没有  就算我真的饿了  也不会吃
No. And if I was, it wouldn't be for something
加了...肌苷酸二钠[风味增强剂]的东西
with... disodium inosinate.
罐子是铝做的
Can is made of aluminum.
而且尺寸非常适合
It's dimensions are perfect
捕捉Wi-Fi信号
for capturing Wi-Fi radio waves.
用这个对准房子
Point this at the house.
他家的Wi-Fi网络有wpa密码保护
His home Wi-Fi network has wpa password protection.
-你能黑进去吗  -刚黑完
- Can you crack it? - Just did.
经常浏览政治专题的网页
Spends a lot of time on political websites,
写了博客讨论国会议员迈克・德兰西
Blogging about a congressman-- Michael Delancey.
是议员先生的黑粉
Not a big fan of the congressman.
这里有料  这有个很大的文件夹
This is interesting. Here's a big file--
加密的
Encrypted.
我得接一下电话
I'm going to have to take this.
马上就回来
I'll be right back.
你好
Hello.
鲍威尔先生吗
Mr. Powell?
我是兼职中介
This is the work time temp agency.
你几周前给我们打过电话应聘宴会工作人员吗
You called us several weeks ago about an event staff position.
-是的  -我们有个为期两天的兼职
- Uh-huh. - We have two-day job placement
你能来吗
for you, if you're still available.
当然能
Absolutely, yes.
他们要你12点半到场
They need you there at 12:30.
听起来很不错  非常感谢
Sounds great. Thank you very much.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
看来鲍威尔终于时来运转了
Looks like Powell's fortunes may be turning around.
希望如此
I hope so.
但我们还是没查出为什么机器给了他的号码
But we still don't know why the machine gave us his number.
警探
Detective?
查过你们那个人了
Looked up your guy.
除了几张交通罚单
Nothing but a couple of traffic tickets
一份步枪申请表  其他什么都没有
and an application for a firearms license
他很清白
For a rifle. Otherwise he's clean.
知道了  谢谢
I see. Okay, thank you.
我要留心这个人吗
Should I be worried about this guy?
我们正在研究  警探
That's what we're trying to determine, detective.
鲍威尔电脑里的那个文件夹
That file from Powell's computer,
是个用加密软件加密过的匿名邮件账户
it was a pgp-encrypted, anonymous email account.
所有邮件都寄往一个地址
All these emails are addressed
德兰西议员的办公室
to ongressman Delancey's office.
是鲍威尔看不顺眼的那个议员吗
The same congressman that Powell had a beef with?
德兰西推行削减预算
Delancey pushed for the budgetary cutbacks
引起了市内的裁员
that prompted the city layoffs.
他让鲍威尔丢了饭碗
He cost Powell his job.
那鲍威尔为什么还要去德兰西的筹资宴会工作
So why would Powell be working a fundraiser for Delancey?
他有登记在案的武器吗
Does he own any registered weapons?
卡特说他申请过枪械执照
Carter said he applied for a firearms license--
步枪...
a rifle...
这些是死亡恐吓信  里瑟先生
These are death threats, mr. Reese.
鲍威尔来这不是为了打工
Powell's not here for a job,
而是来暗杀德兰西
He's going to assassinate Delancey.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese
你找到鲍威尔了吗
Did you find Powell?
我们得在他搞定议员之前搞定他
We need to get to him before he gets to the congressman.
先生
Sir.
请您接受安检
You need to come through the main line.
谢谢
Thanks.
我们有了点麻烦  芬奇
We've got a problem, Finch,
鲍威尔已经进去了
Powell's already inside.
那我们也得想办法进去
We should probably get in there then.
你跟紧议员
You stay close to the congressman.
保持警惕  随时准备行动
Keep your eyes open and be ready to move.
什么行动  如果有人开枪
Move? If somebody starts shooting,
我该怎么做
what exactly do you expect me to do?
你得自己想办法  芬奇
You'll think of something, Finch.
票数不错啊  迈克
Polls look good, Mike.
多亏您的支持  参议员先生
Thanks to your endorsement, senator.
你还记得我的竞选经理彼得・马西森吗
Do you remember Pete Matheson my campaign manager?
当然  你干得棒极了
Sure. You're doing a hell of a job.
十分感谢  参议员先生  谢谢您的鼓励
Oh, thank you, senator. Thank you very much.
鲍威尔肯定拿着东西下楼了
Powell must be downstairs with the stuff.
-你还跟着德兰西吗  -很靠近
- Are you with Delancey? - Close by.
听着  迈克
Listen, listen, Mike.
如果你听得懂  我恳请你帮个忙
Uh, as long as a got you, let me ask you a favor.
别再说那些套话  明白吗
Back off the rhetoric, understand?
拍那些捐赠人的马屁确实有助于你的演说
Calling out certain large donors makes for great stumping,
但也让人感觉很不舒服
But it also makes people uncomfortable.
"人"特指你吧
By "people," you mean you?
你记住我的话  议员
Just keep it in mind, congressman.
我们都希望你能长久坐稳你的位置
We want you to have a long, long career.
听着  有件事很奇怪
Listen, this is odd.
那些鲍威尔寄给议员的
Those threatening emails that Powell sent
恐吓邮件
to the congressman--
我正在用我自己的系统标记它们
They're being flagged by my system.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
请就坐
We'd like you to please take your seats.
女士们先生们
Hello, ladies and gentlemen.
感谢您赏光前来出席宴会
Thank you for joining us this afternoon.
我是彼得・马西森
I'm Pete Matheson.
几年前
You know, a few years back,
我的好朋友兼生意伙伴来找我  说
My friend and business partner came to me and said,
"我想参加竞选"
"Hey, I'm thinking of running for office."
...很受欢迎
...Popular,
我们都认为他们一直以来...
I think we can all agree that they have always been...
IP地址没有问题
The IP addresses match,
但TTL值完全不对
but there are big discrepancies in the TTL values,
数据头也无法通过验证
And the headers are failing to authenticate.
你说什么呢  芬奇
What are you getting at, Finch?
那些匿名邮件
Those anonymous emails didn't originate
不是从鲍威尔的笔记本发出
in Powell's laptop.
而是从一个远端位置复制过去
They were copied onto it from a remote location.
芬奇  比起纠结这位持枪歹徒的电脑
Finch, I'm more interested in finding the guy with the gun
我更想赶快找到他的人
than I am in fixing his computer.
迈克・德兰西议员
Congressman Michael Delancey.
谢谢  感谢各位今天的光临
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you for coming.
也谢谢你
And thank you too.
我认为他的系统被人黑过
I think his system's been hacked.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese?
-彩色纸屑  -我认为鲍威尔被陷害了
- Confetti? - I think Powell's being set up.
他在那儿  在那儿
There he is! There!
在露台上
In the balcony!
我不知道议员伤势如何
I can't tell how badly the congressman is wounded.
我也跟丢了杀手
Yeah, I lost the real shooter.
电邮  工作  鲍威尔被陷害了
The emails, the job-- Powell was set up.
听我说  不是我
Listen to me! It wasn't me!
我什么也没干
I didn't do anything!
你们为什么不听我说
Why won't you listen to me?
问题是  谁陷害了他
The question is, by who?
这真是令人震惊和悲痛
This is a shocking and a tragic day.
我们都在祈祷他能撑过去
We're all just praying that he'll pull through.
就这些
That's--that's all.
无论是谁枪击了德兰西议员
Whoever shot Congressman Delancey
并陷害了鲍威尔  他们费了一番功夫
and framed Powell went to a lot of trouble.
他们必须侵入他的电脑
They had to hack his computer,
伪造他的网络搜索记录和电邮
They spoofed his internet search history and emails.
他们很清楚要篡改什么信息
They knew exactly what information to manipulate
能让警察以为他有罪
so that he looked guilty to the police.
也骗过了我们  和你的机器
Fooled us... and your machine.
不  机器不会被骗
No, the machine doesn't get fooled.
如果鲍威尔不是威胁  那他肯定有危险
If Powell isn't the threat, then he must be in danger.
他是替罪羊
Well, he's the patsy then.
也许他本不该从筹款会生还
Maybe he wasn't supposed to make it out of the fundraiser alive.
你看到枪手了吗
Did you get a look at the shooter?
身手不算好  不过他是个职业杀手
Not a good one. But he was a pro.
枪法准  有预定逃跑路线
Deadeye shot with a preplanned escape route.
跟我们的黑客技能有别  所以
Different skill set than our hacker, so...
不同的人
Different people?
我们面对的是个团队
We're looking at a team.
首先要弄清楚
First thing to determine
黑客是怎么入侵他电脑的
is how the hacker got into his computer.
可能要花一点时间
This may take me a little time.
我看下鲍威尔的情况
I'll check on Powell.
你  我还以为能相信你
You. I thought I could trust you.
你家那位还要我不用担心鲍威尔
Your partner said I shouldn't worry about Powell.
结果他枪击了一名议员
Then he goes and shoots a congressman.
现在联邦特工把他带到我的管区了
And now the feds brought him in to my precinct.
不是他干的  我当时在场
He didn't do it. I was there.
我们有整个宴会厅的目击证人
Well, we got a banquet hall full of witnesses
-持不同意见  -好吧  他被陷害了
- saying otherwise. - Right. Well, he was set up.
-被陷害  谁陷害的  -还不清楚
- Set up? By who? - We don't know yet.
不过我们需要帮助
But we could use some help.
我基本上也无能为力
There's not much I can do.
联邦特工全权负责此案
The feds are running this show.
他们现在正在审讯他
They're taking him into interrogation now.
我得知道他们在说什么
I need to know what they're saying.
我说过了  我无能为力
I told you, there's nothing I can do.
卡特  这是在救一个无辜的人
Carter, it could help save an innocent man.
我没有开枪
I didn't shoot anyone.
这是现场发现的你的步枪
It was your rifle found at the scene.
我根本没有步枪
I don't own a rifle!
是用你的名字登记的
It's registered in your name.
-肯定是那个人  -哪个人
- It must have been the guy. - Uh, which guy exactly?
你说攻击你的那个  还是在那里工作的那个
The one you say attacked you? Or the who worked there.
不  是那个  那个在那里工作的人
No, the guy who--who-- who worked there
是他带我去包厢准备彩纸炮的
who took me up to the balcony to rig the confetti cannon.
没人看到过那人
No one on the staff saw this guy.
所有的监控录相上都没有
And he's not in any security footage.
他就在那里
He was right there.
我看到他了
I saw him.
他肯定是知道摄像头位置
He must have known where the cameras were.
整件事都是个陷阱
This whole thing is a setup.
你们给人力中介打电话了吗
Did you call the staffing agency?
三州区域根本没有任何一家
There's no record of any company named Work Time
叫"工作时间"的公司
in the tristate area.
这不可能  他们打电话给我了
That's impossible. They called me.
你的手套呢
What about your gloves?
为什么上面验出枪弹残留
Why'd they test positive for gunshot residue?
我不知道  是那个人给我的
I don't know. I got them from the guy.
是啊是啊  那个人
Right, right. The guy.
你还在吗
You still there?
在  怎么了
Yeah. What happened?
医院打电话来了
Hospital just called.
德兰西议员没能挺过去
Congressman Delancey didn't make it.
鲍威尔面临一级谋杀指控
Powell's looking at murder one.
莱丝  是我
Les, it's me.
我的上帝  斯科特  你在哪儿
Oh, my God, Scott, where are you?
这是个天大的误会
It's all a big mistake.
FBI正在搜查我们的房子
The FBI is searching the house.
-新闻说你枪杀了一个人  -不  听我说
- The news says you shot someone. - No, listen.
他们说的都是谎言  莱丝丽
These things they're saying, Leslie, they're all lies.
-不是真的  孩子们跟你在一起吗  -在
- No. Are the kids with you? - Yes.
我想你把他们带到一边  好吗
I want you to take them next door, okay?
-好的  -听我说
- Okay. - Now, listen.
他们可能会要你跟他们走
They're probably going to ask you to go with them
问你一些问题
and answer some questions.
莱丝丽  听我说
Now, Leslie-- Leslie, listen to me.
按他们的要求做  明白吗
You do what they ask, okay?
明白
Okay.
你还有台电脑吗
You have another computer?
没有  什么电脑
No. Wh--what computer?
-怎么回事  斯科特  -我不知道
- What's going on, Scott? - I don't know.
我需要你相信我  好吗
I need you to trust me, okay?
一切都会好起来的
Everything's going to be all right.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
怎么了
What is it?
我认为鲍威尔仍然有危险
I think Powell could still be in danger.
什么危险
How so?
栽赃陷害这档子事  被陷害人通常都活不了
In frame jobs, the decoy usually doesn't make it.
如果他们现场没搞定
If they're not taken out at the scene,
之后也要马上补救
They're eliminated soon after...
弄成自杀或是意外的样子
Staged to look like a suicide or accident.
这是你的经验之谈吗  里瑟先生
Are you speaking from experience, Mr. Reese?
重点是解决未解决的问题
Point is it ties up the loose ends.
有了  我想我有办法找到那黑客了
Here. I think I may have found a way to our hacker.
什么办法
How?
一个木马程序  藏在鲍威尔的电邮里
A Trojan Horse...hidden in one of Powell's emails.
招聘会邀请
Invitation to a job fair?
鲍威尔一回复  木马就安装上了
When Powell rsvped, the Trojan was installed.
会在他电脑上打开一个端口供黑客出入
It opened a port on his computer that allowed the hacker access.
我现在安装一个同样的木马
I'm now installing that same Trojan.
你蓄意感染自己的电脑
You purposely infected your own computer?
不是  我构建一个虚拟系统
No, I created a virtual system.
现在木马还在运行  我们可以看它引向何方
Now the Trojan can still run, and we can see where it leads.
-那名黑客那里  -没错
- Back to the hacker. - Yes.
代码相当复杂
Wow. The coding is so complex.
非常聪明
It's really clever.
不过还不够聪明  我们连接上了
But not clever enough-- we're connected.
能拿到地址吗
Can you get their location?
不行  IP地址伪装过了
No, the IP address is masked.
不过我们能看到他们在看什么
But we can see what they're looking at.
好像是建筑的平面图
Looks like a floor plan.
芬奇  这是市中心的联邦法院
Finch, that's a federal courthouse downtown.
卡特说联调局现在
Carter said the FBI was now running
全权负责鲍威尔一案
the Powell investigation.
如果你真认为鲍威尔是无辜的
If you really think Powell is innocent
就得快点弄到证据了
you need to come up with some evidence fast.
-他还在你局里吗  -之前在
- Is he still in your custody? - He was.
-联邦探员把他带走了  -要带到哪里
- The feds have him. - Where are they taking him?
法院  明天传讯
The courthouse, for arraignment tomorrow.
-为什么问这个  你想干什么  -谢了
- Why? What are you thinking? - Thanks.
鲍威尔在FBI手上
The FBI's got Powell.
他们根本不知道这是把他
They have no idea they're dropping him off
往杀手手里送
into the hands of the assassins.
我能做什么
What can I do?
把第八分局到法院之间
Send me the most direct route
最短路线发给我
from the eighth precinct to the courthouse.
正在办
I'm doing it now.
小心  小心
Watch out! Watch out!
是你阻止了我  你是谁
You're the guy who tackled me. Who are you?
唯一知道你无辜的人
One of the only people who know you're innocent.
你想要怎么样
What do you want?
现在  把你送到安全的地方
Right now, to get you to someplace safe.
安全
Safe?
你从FBI手里绑架了我
You just kidnapped me from the FBI.
说吧  芬奇  鲍威尔在我这里
Go ahead, Finch. I've got Powell.
我还没办法解码黑客的IP地址
I haven't been able to unmask the hacker's IP.
不过防火墙有个弱点
But here's a vulnerability in the firewall.
成功
Yes.
好了  我们进去了
Okay, now we're in.
就知道你能行
Never doubted you.
现在  看看藏在幕后的是谁
Now let's see who's behind the curtain.
等等  不对劲
Wait, something's wrong.
怎么了
What is it?
我们没进去  是被放进去了
We didn't hack in, we were let in.
那是诱饵
It's a honeypot.
程序非常复杂
Program is sophisticated.
他们用蠕虫
They're using a worm
感染了连接我们专用网络的全部设备
to infect any devices connected to our private network.
包括我们的手机
Including our phones.
他们现在能听到我们说话
They're listening to us right now.
-毁掉你的手机  -等等
- Destroy your phone. - Wait.
你知道怎么找到我
You know how to find me.
你是谁
Who are you?
这个我要了
I'll take this one.
零钱不用找
Keep the change.
212-555-0159
212  555  0159
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thanks. - You're welcome.
给  带上
Here. Put this on.
你现在是全纽约的最大通缉犯
You're the most wanted man in New York.
212-555-0159
212  555  0159
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese.
芬奇  到底是怎么回事
Finch, what the hell happened?
恐怕我低估了那个黑客
I'm afraid I underestimated our hacker.
因此
As a consequence,
我在图书馆的设备被暴露了
my equipment at the library is compromised.
所以暂时  我只能机动行事
So for the time being, I'm mobile.
我觉得我们现在需要额外帮助
Listen, I felt like we might need a little extra help
以追查杀死德兰西议员的凶手
looking for Congressman Delancey's killer,
所以我打给了一位专家
So I've called in a specialist--
一位对政治领域有深入了解的人
Someone with an intimate knowledge of the political arena.
她来了  失陪
Oh, here she is. I have to go.
等等  什么专家  还是女的
Wait a minute. Specialist? She?
芬奇
Finch?
这房间我预定了
Hey, I reserved the room.
课间休息一下
Take a study break.
有你的  老兄
Nice work, dude.
请
Please.
感谢您这么急赶过来  摩根女士
Thank you for meeting me on such short notice, Ms. Morgan.
有人需要时我就工作  您是
I work when I'm needed, Mr.--
请叫我哈罗德
Harold-- please.
我有点好奇您如何拿到我的号码
I am curious how you got my number.
共同的朋友那里  他帮过你
Mutual friend. He assisted you on a...
跟某家制药公司进行过  微妙的谈判
delicate negotiation with a certain pharmaceutical company.
原来你就是电话里的那个人
So you're the guy on the other end of the phone.
约翰最近如何
How is John?
在外奔波  一如既往
On the run, as usual.
即使是现在  他也还在
He's actually helping another one of our clients
帮我们的一名客户
even as we speak.
正如他之前能帮助你一样
And, in the same way that he was able to assist you,
我们希望您能回报一下
we were hoping that you might be able to return the favor.
我不明白
I don't understand.
一个人当着你们所有人的面把我丈夫带走了
One man took my husband away from all of you?
我们相信他是某武装团伙的一员
We believe he's part of an armed group--
可能是恐怖分子
possibly terrorists.
您丈夫是否有某些
Did your husband have any...
激进的政治观点  鲍威尔夫人
radical political views, Mrs. Powell?
恐怖分子  不
Terrorists? No.
斯科特不可能跟这类事情有关
Scott would never be involved in anything like that.
你要是不相信我  就去问他的朋友  同事
If you don't believe me, ask his friends, his coworkers.
您不知道您丈夫已经失业
You do know that your husband's been out of work
八个月了吗
for the past eight months?
不可能  斯科特每天都去上班
No. Scott goes to work every day.
您最近看过自己的财产情况吗
Have you taken a look at your finances recently?
很明显  您并没有自己以为地那么
It seems pretty clear that you don't know your husband
了解您的丈夫  鲍威尔夫人
as well as you think, Mrs. Powell.
我们的客户之前在德兰西的筹款会上
Our client was at Congressman Delancey's fundraiser.
-是客人吗  -是那个枪手
- As a guest? - The shooter.
他是被陷害的
He was framed.
我们正在找真正的凶手
We're looking for the actual shooter.
你们两个还真喜欢挑战  不是吗
Well, you boys certainly do like a challenge, don't you?
我已经列出了可能的嫌犯名单
I've come up with a list of alternative suspects--
想要议员死的人
people who might have wanted the congressman dead.
这些人之间的关系
Well, all of these people have been
都紧张地要置对方于死地
at each other's throats at some point.
杀死德兰西的人  肯定不只是为了政治
Whoever killed Delancey, it goes way beyond politics.
在竞选之前
Prior to running for office,
德兰西有一家承包公司
Delancey owned a contracting company.
地方检察官已经秘密准备了几个月
D.A.'s office has quietly been preparing an investigation
想要调查这间公司
into the company for several months.
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
-当我没说  -有各种关于检查员
- Never mind. - There were allegations of corner cutting
吃回扣和受贿的指控
and payoffs to city inspectors.
德兰西做生意的方式还真奇怪
Strange way for Delancey to run his business,
考虑到他的反腐败立场
Considering his anti-corruption platform.
确实
It is.
但他并不实际掌控生意
But he wasn't running the business.
-是马西森  -德兰西的竞选总经理
- Matheson -- Delancey's campaign manager.
外加他的生意伙伴
And business partner.
两年来
For two years,
德兰西一直专心竞选
Delancey is in full-time campaign mode--
没什么精力来打理企业的日常事务
Not really running the day-to-day of his business.
那么回扣跟贿赂就
So the bribes and the corner cutting--
肯定是在马西森任下出现
They must have happened under Matheson's watch.
除非他能抹黑德兰西
Unless he could say Delancey was really running things.
而且现在德兰西都死了  没法为自己辩护了
Which he could if Delancey wasn't around to defend himself.
就算这些都是事实
Even if this was true,
我们也没有证据证明是马西森杀了德兰西
We have no proof that Matheson had Delancey killed.
去搞证据不就完了
Let's go get some.
不好意思  借过
Excuse me, sorry.
为什么你丈夫要这么做
Why'd your husband do this?
抱歉我  求你们了
I'm sorry. Just--just please.
议员是他杀的么
Did he really kill him?
我想不通
I don't get it.
为什么有人会对我做这种事情
Why would anyone want to do this to me?
他们要个替罪羊  你正好合适
They needed a patsy. And you fit the role.
他们
They?
谁是他们
Who's they?
抓紧  我们走
Come on. Let's go!
我们都表示沉痛哀悼
We're all feeling terrible...
确保所有人能想呆多久就呆多久
Just make sure that everybody can stay as long as they want.
我必须得会办公室去了  好么
I just got to get back to the office, okay?
好  好
Okay, good.
打扰了
Excuse me.
-马西森先生  -我很遗憾
- Mr. Matheson.  - Look, I'm sorry.
-我已经说过了  -我不是记者
- I've said everything-- - I'm not a reporter.
我名叫佐伊・摩根
My name is Zoe Morgan.
我帮过你的朋友  杰・泰纳  就在去年
I helped a friend of yours-- Jay Tanner--last year.
父子纠纷那件案子
Little matter of a paternity suit.
想起来了  不过我确信
Oh, yes, well, I'm sure we don't need
这里不需要你的服务  谢谢
Those services right now, thank you.
父子纠纷并不是我的强项
Paternity suits aren't my specialty.
危机处理才是
Crisis management is.
而现在  我觉得正是你要的
And right now, I think that's exactly what you need.
行
All right.
行  摩根女士  你倒是跟我说说我为什么要你的服务
All right, Ms. Morgan, why don't you tell me why I need you.
一  你即将面临的
One-- your impending investigation
来自地检官的调查
With the D.A.'s office.
-我这方面有律师照应  -二
- I have lawyers on retainer. - Two--
杀害你的生意伙伴
The killing of your business partner--
国会议员德兰西
Congressman Delancey.
什么
Excuse me?
德兰西有可能出面做证
Delancey would have testified that you were the one
是你搞的开后门和贿赂
Behind the shortcuts and payoffs.
现在他死了  你就能栽赃给他了
Now that he's dead, you can lay the blame on him.
你特么以为你自己是谁啊
Who the hell do you think you are?
你搭档要坑了你  你就先下手为强
Your partner was going to burn you, so you burned him first.
我懂  但是你雇来的人呢
I get it. But your vendor?
你雇来的人搞砸了
Your vendor dropped the ball.
你找来背黑锅的人已经蒸发了
The man that you set up is missing-in-action.
我说  如果你想做坏事
You know, if you're going to do something wrong,
那就好好做
Do it right.
我能找到鲍威尔
I can find Powell.
把他交给你或者任何你指定的人
Bring him to you or whomever you like.
当然是要收费的
For a price, of course.
我不知道你什么意思
I don't know what you're referring to.
但你最好现在就走开
And I think it's time that you leave.
留着名片吧
Keep the card.
没准就能用上
Might come in handy.
我已经跟你讲的很清楚了
I thought I was clear on how this works--
单向联系  不是你来找我
I call you, not the other way around.
我雇你是因为我觉得你能搞定
I hired you because I thought you could handle this.
我确实搞的定
And I am.
那怎么那鲍威尔还活着
Then why is Powell still alive?
你跟我保证过你的能力
You assured me of your abilities.
而现在  我连个屁都没看见
And right now, I'm not seeing any of them.
我能截留你的一切电子邮件
I could have every email you've sent,
一切联系人  一切密码
Contact you've called and password you've used.
我能掏空你的银行账户
I could empty your bank accounts,
套现你的股票  还能给你的前妻
Liquidate your stocks, and even send your ex-wife
发你那百慕大豪宅的地址
The location of your house in Bermuda.
行  够了  够了  算你厉害
All right, stop it, stop it. You've made your point.
鲍威尔和他的朋友我会搞定
Powell and his friend will be taken care of.
你只要去给我准备好尾款就行了
You just make sure to have my final payment ready.
你在哪
Where are you?
我在去市中心
I'm headed downtown.
客户开始紧张了
The client's getting nervous.
他们刚在23街和8道交汇口附近上了地铁
They just dropped into the subway at 23rd and 8th.
收到
Got it.
这是个发信机
It's a transmitter.
刚才旅馆那人就是这么追踪过来的
That's how the guy at the hotel found us.
可能是今天刚装上的
Could have planted it today,
也可能更早
Maybe sometime earlier.
没准是在你家装的
Probably at your house.
他们还去过我家
They've been to my house?
很明显幕后黑手做的滴水不漏
Whoever is behind this left little to chance.
但现在我要你专注  斯科特
But I need you to stay focused, Scott,
这样我才能把你安全带回家
So I can get you back to your family.
我很怀疑我现在还有没有家可回
I doubt I got a family to go back to right now.
我知道你没了工作
I know about your job.
我知道你很拮据  还有你的谎言
I know about the money, the lies.
对  我知道这就像生活在谎言中一样
Yeah, I know what it's like to live inside a lie.
我就这么过了很久
I've lived there for so long,
觉得都已经没有出路了
It feels like there's no way out.
但事实是有的
But there always is.
我只要一点点的时间  明白吗
I just needed a little more time, you know.
找个工作  重新振作
To get a job, to get on my feet.
我原本打算告诉莱丝丽
I was going to tell Leslie.
但现在一切都晚了
But now it's too late.
还不算晚
No, it's not.
我们会帮你脱离困境
We're going to get you out of this.
那些人
These people...
他们连国会议员都杀
They killed a Congressman.
你还能跟我保证他们不会杀我吗
Are you going to promise me that they won't kill us too?
我可不这么想
I didn't think so.
我要跟我老婆打电话  就现在
I need to talk to my wife. Now.
没可能  现在不行
That's not possible. Not right now.
我们得小心低调
We need to keep our heads down.
我会死的
I could die.
而我一生中最爱的那个人
And--and the person who I love most in life
会以为我不过是一个杀手
Would think that I'm nothing more than a killer.
你知不知道那会有多痛苦
Do you have any idea what that feels like?
其实  我知道
Actually, I do.
当然  就我来说
Of course, in my case,
我的确是个杀手
It was true.
现在  赶紧  我们走
Now, come on, let's go.
请勿靠近门口
Stand away from the door.
我是卡特
Carter.
你好 警探
Hello, Detective.
你特么的在想什么
What the hell were you thinking...
武装劫囚
Taking down a prisoner transfer?
管用就行  听好  我要你帮忙
It worked. Listen, I need a favor.
鲍威尔想跟他老婆说话
Powell needs to talk to his wife.
-就现在  -你疯了
- Now.  - Are you crazy?
你明知道联调局在监听她的电话
You know the feds are up on her phone.
他很需要  卡特
He needs this, Carter.
鲍威尔夫人
Mrs. Powell.
你是不是把你的孩子留给邻居照顾了
Did you leave your kids with your neighbor?
是的  出什么事了么
Yes. Is something wrong?
没有  他们打电话过来报平安
No, uh, they're just calling to check in.
跟我来
Follow me.
喂
Hello?
莱丝丽  是我
Hi, Leslie. Hi. It's me.
斯科特  你在哪
Scott? Where are you?
我很好  听我说
I'm okay. Listen...
莱丝丽  我是真的  真的很抱歉
Leslie, I'm really, really sorry.
老天啊  斯科特  是你开的枪吗
Oh, my god, Scott, did you shoot that man?
不  不  当然不是我
No, no, of course not.
-这你可得相信我  莱丝丽  -我还信
- You got to believe me, Les.  - Do I?
你不上班都有八个月了  S斯科特
You've been out of work for eight months, Scott.
你每天早上都去干什么了
What have you been doing every morning?
找工作  到处都找遍了
Looking for work-- anywhere and everywhere.
那我们的信用卡呢  储蓄呢
And our credit cards? Our savings?
我知道  宝贝  我知道
I know, babe, I know.
为什么  斯科特
Why, scott?
因为我不能
Because I couldn't...
我没法告诉你我被炒了
I couldn't tell you that I was fired.
我以为我们之间无话不谈的
I thought we told each other everything.
我知道  听着  莱丝丽
I know. Listen, Leslie,
我会把这事搞定  我保证
I'm going to make this right, I promise.
剩下的你还是当面跟她讲吧
You can tell her the rest in person.
我们要走了
We need to move now.
我得走了  我爱你
I gotta go. I love you.
斯科特
Scott?
打扰下  我叫S鲍威尔
Excuse me. My name is Scott Powell.
站住  不许动
Stay where you are! Do not turn around!
举起手来
Raise your hands!
-车子在等我们  -收到
- Transport's waiting on us. - You got it.
都解决了
Is it finished?
还差一点
Not quite.
不过我想很快了
But I suspect it will be soon.
看邮箱
我雇你
I hired you
是因为我觉得你能搞定
Because I thought you could handle this.
我确实搞的定
And I am.
那怎么那鲍威尔还活着
Then why is Powell still alive?
你跟我保证过你的能力
You assured me of your abilities.
而现在  我连个屁都没看见
And right now, I'm not seeing any of them.
吾友如晤:
事既至此某实罪过  囹圄愧疚实难以表
彼得・马西森
他来了
There he is!
好了  朋友们都合作点  麻烦退后
All right, folks, get back, please.
- 先生  能谈谈吗  -回家开心吗
- Sir--Can you make a statement? - Glad to be home, sir?
鲍威尔先生  回到家的感觉怎么样
Hey, Mr. Powell, what's it like to be home, sir?
-回家开心吗  -你有被威胁过么
- Glad to be home? - Did you get any threats?
你接下来会怎么应对这些事情
What are you going to do in reaction to this?
-佐伊  -约翰
- Zoe. - John.
我听说能抓到马西森还得多亏了你
I hear we have you to thank for catching Matheson.
乐意效劳
Glad I could help.
不过薪酬问题还是得讨论一下
Although there is a matter of payment.
请我喝一杯
Buy me a drink?
你想念你的妻子吗
Did you miss your wife?
当然想了
Of course I missed my wife.
你跟我说过有个人只说了两个字
You once told me a story about a guy who could say two words
就打发走了那些记者
That would make the reporters go away.
就是想知道是哪两个字
Ever figure out what he said?
你想念你的妻子吗
Did you miss your wife?
我看到了鲍威尔先生被释放的消息
I see that Mr. Powell has been released.
他前面的路还长着呢
Still has a long road ahead of him, though.
确实
Indeed.
但是我认为他很快就能回归正轨
But I suspect that soon he'll be on his way back.
我掌握的一个公司正准备
I control a company that's decided
在纽约建个新设施
To build a new facility in New York.
他们倒需要鲍威尔这样的人来管事
They could use a man like Powell overseeing things.
你可真高尚  芬奇
That's noble of you, Finch.
谈不上  我只是欣赏好人  里瑟先生
Hardly. I just value good people, Mr. Reese.
那个黑客有进展么
You follow up on the hacker?
她似乎跟你有的一拼  滑得很
She seems to cover her tracks as efficiently as you do.
我倒是追踪到了一个地址
I was able to trace the signal to an address
然后匿名知会了联调局
Which the FBI received by way of an... anonymous tip.
遗憾的是  他们还是晚了
Sadly, they were too late.
目前看来是黑客用的是一名毫不知情的
It seems the hacker was using the dorm room
女大学生所用的寝室
Of an unsuspecting college student
她寒假回家去了
Who had been on winter break.
我要去评估我的系统损失
I need to determine the damage to my system.
再有号码出来的时候我会来找你
I'll contact you when another number comes up.
保重  芬奇
Take care, Finch.
你好
联调局走访了我  不过幸亏我没什么行李
你是谁
我的名字  我有很多  你叫我根好了
是你杀了马西森
马西森的死是他自己的软弱害的
你为什么联系我
我想来承认你这个合格的对手
并表示我很期待下一次
下一次
"Next time."
哈罗德
连线终止
疑犯追踪 第1季 第13集
Person of Interest S01E13 720p HDTV x264
-= YYeTs人人字幕 =-